<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Quotes>
    <Quote>
        <id>2</id>
        <Source />
        <Contents>"There is no deep knowing of God without a deep knowing of self and no deep knowing of self without a deep knowing of God."

               -John Calvin 
</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>4</id>
        <Source />
        <Contents>Those who are waiting [in Scripture] are waiting very actively.  They know that what they are waiting for is growing from the ground on which they are standing...The secret of waiting is the faith that the seed has been planted, that something has begun.  

Active waiting means to be present fully to the moment, in the conviction that something is happening where you are and that you want to be present to it."
    - Henri Nouwen</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>5</id>
        <Source>-Max Lucado, "FEARLESS"</Source>
        <Contents>"Real courage embraces the twin realities of current difficulty and ultimate triumph.  Yes, life stinks.  But it won't last forever.  As one of my friends likes to say,'Everything will work out in the end.  If it's not working out, it's not the end.'" </Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>11/12/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>7</id>
        <Source>-Mother Teresa</Source>
        <Contents>Every day we are called to do small things with great love.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>8</id>
        <Source>Brother Lawrence, "The Practice of the Presence of God"</Source>
        <Contents>Let all our employment be to know God; the more one knows Him, the more one desires to know Him.  And as knowledge is commonly the measure of love, the deeper and more extensive our knowledge shall be, the greater will be our love; and if our love of God were great, we should love Him equally in pains and pleasures.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>9</id>
        <Source>-Teresa of Avila</Source>
        <Contents>"All difficulties in prayer can be traced to one cause: praying as if God were absent."</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>10</id>
        <Source>James S. Behrens, "Portraits of Grace"</Source>
        <Contents>"We have a tendency to want to heal and fill and satisfy.  Maybe God has come closer than we think.  Everything that is empty has left room for God to arrive, again and again."</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>1/31/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>11</id>
        <Source>-John Bunyan</Source>
        <Contents>"You can do more than pray, after you have prayed, but you cannot do more than pray until you have prayed."</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>12</id>
        <Source>-J. Heinrich Arnold, "Bread and Wine: Readings for Easter and Lent"</Source>
        <Contents>"His cross is the center, the linchpin, of the struggle between God and Satan, and as such it must become the center of our hearts too.  In the cross alone is victory!  In the cross alone is purity!  It is there that the hosts of evil are overcome; that Christ's love to each human being springs eternal and gives us peace...Jesus does not offer a philosophy, but life.  He is real food.  He will change everything for someone who experiences this, not only for that moment but for all eternity."</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>5/10/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>13</id>
        <Source>-Blaise Pascal</Source>
        <Contents>Kind words do not cost much.  Yet they accomplish much.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>6/12/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>14</id>
        <Source>-Richard Foster</Source>
        <Contents>A blazing God-consciousness frees us from self-consciousness.  It is freedom.  It is joy.  It is life.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>6/22/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>15</id>
        <Source>-Randy Alcorn, HEAVEN</Source>
        <Contents>You may think that you don't deserve forgiveness after all you've done.  That's exactly right.  No one deserves forgiveness...That's the point of grace.  On the cross, Jesus experienced the Hell we deserve, so that for eternity we can experience the Heaven we don't deserve.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>8/23/2013</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>16</id>
        <Source>-Judy Squier, His Majesty in Brokenness</Source>
        <Contents>The truth is God is the only hope for any family.  He's the only One who can keep that dear octopus from self-destruction.  Are you ready to hand yours over to Him?  When you do, you can exchange disappointment for the good news that your brokenness sets the perfect stage for God's redemptive work.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>1/4/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>17</id>
        <Source>Brennan Manning, quoted in WATCH  FOR THE LIGHT: Readings for Advent &amp; Christmas</Source>
        <Contents>"Unless you...become like little children, you will never enter the kingdom of heaven" (Matt. 18:3).  Jesus is not suggesting that heaven is a vast playground for infants.  Children are our model because they have no claim of heaven.  If they are close to God, Simon Tugwell says, "it is not because they are innocent, but because they are incompetent..."
 
Excerpt from "Shipwrecked at the Stable" by Brennan Manning</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>18</id>
        <Source>- Ben Patterson, in "Holy War" where he talks about his son's struggle with Tourette's syndrome</Source>
        <Contents>"...Both anger and tenderness are forms of passion.  As is prayer.  God doesn't mind our anger.  He even relishes it, if it drives us to him instead of away from him.  Better an outburst than a theologically correct and spiritually pallid rationale, and a dangling conversation.
   No wonder we can get so bored with prayer.  God is bored too.  He wants to engage our hearts, not just our brains."</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>19</id>
        <Source>Dr. David Stoop, HOPE FOR THE PERFECTIONIST</Source>
        <Contents>Most people operate on the assumption that events in life cause them to feel what they feel and do what they do.  Research by Aaron Beck and David Burns has shown that this is not so.  People feel what they feel and do what they do because of the way they think.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>4/30/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>20</id>
        <Source>Elisabeth Elliot, www.ElisabethElliot..org</Source>
        <Contents>God came down and lived in this same world as a man. He showed us how to live in this world, subject to its vicissitudes and necessities, that we might be changed-not into an angel or a storybook princess, not wafted into another world, but changed into saints in this world. The secret is Christ in me, not me in a different set of circumstances.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>6/10/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>21</id>
        <Source>-Jan Johnson, WHEN THE SOUL LISTENS,p.69</Source>
        <Contents>Contemplative prayer is not about tingly experiences; rather, it centers in loving God and enjoying God's presence.  The chief end of contemplation, wrote seventeenth century Puritan theologian Richard Baxter, is "acquaintance and fellowship with God."
     Paying attention to God is similar to paying attention in a human love relationship.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/11/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>22</id>
        <Source>- Ann Voskamp, http://www.aholyexperience.com </Source>
        <Contents>For those who can see, the world’s beauty outweighs its burdens, its grace greater than its grime.

              -</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>23</id>
        <Source>-James B. Smith, THE GOOD AND BEAUTIFUL GOD</Source>
        <Contents>When we join our story to God's, the story in which our good and beautiful God gets the last word, then everything begins to make sense.  The pain is still real, but it becomes bearable.  We can then, in time, begin to move on.  And we can begin to see beyond the suffering and look toward the widespread mercy that surrounds us.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>24</id>
        <Source>-Macrina Wiederkehr</Source>
        <Contents>The most helpful discovery of today has been that right in the midst of my sorrows there is always room for joy.  Joy and sorrow are sisters, they live in the same house.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>25</id>
        <Source>-Mother Teresa</Source>
        <Contents>     All you life I [God] have been looking for your love--I have never stopped seeking to and be loved by you.  You have tried many other things in your search for happiness, why not try opening your heart to me, right now, more than you ever have before...
     Come to me with your misery and your sins, with your trouble and needs, and with all your longing to be loved.  I stand at the door of your heart and knock.  Open to me, for I thirst for you.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>8/30/2013</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>26</id>
        <Source>- Ann Voskamp, http://www.aholyexperience.com</Source>
        <Contents>     Because only a life contemplating the love of Christ becomes a life acting the love of Christ.

     Because all radical Christianity is first rooted in relationship Christianity — with Christ and His children. Right where we are. And love always moves. Always rippling outward, onward, forever homeward.

6/15/11 Post</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>27</id>
        <Source>-David Eckman, PhD, Sex, Food &amp; God, p. 210</Source>
        <Contents>God is a God of reality.  He wants integration.  What we do should be in harmony with who we are.  So He continually deals with what is going on within us....He is not satisfied with mindless, robotic obedience.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>28</id>
        <Source>-Richard Stearns, The Hole in Our Gospel</Source>
        <Contents>“There is no ‘whole gospel’ without compassion and justice shown to the poor. It’s that simple.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>8/29/2013</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>29</id>
        <Source>-James B. Smith, THE GOOD AND BEAUTIFUL GOD, p. 7</Source>
        <Contents>When we join our story to God's, the story in which our good and beautiful God gets the last word, then everything begins to make sense.  The pain is still real, but it becomes bearable.  We can then, in time, begin to move on.  And we can begin to see beyond the suffering and look toward the widespread mercy that surrounds us.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>30</id>
        <Source>-Francis Chan, Crazy Love</Source>
        <Contents>When you are pursuing love, running toward Christ, you do not have the opportunity to wonder, Am I doing this right? or Did I serve enough this week?  When you are running toward Christ, you are freed up to serve, love, and give thanks without guilt, worry, or fear.  As long as you are running [toward Christ], you are safe...
As we begin to focus more on Christ, loving Him and others becomes more natural.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>8/15/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>31</id>
        <Source>Michele Perry, 6/16/11 Post from the unpaved road</Source>
        <Contents>If I stop and see and love, one at a time it will be enough.  See one, feed one, cry with one, hold one, LOVE ONE.  It is not always about great victory and miracles.  Sometimes it is just about great love.   About being willing to let your heart break again, and again, and again.  If there is no heart break, there can be no real joy.
http://fromtheunpavedroad.com/2011/06/16/heart-break/</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>11/26/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>32</id>
        <Source>David G. Benner, The Gift of Being Yourself</Source>
        <Contents>Spiritual transformation, not self-knowledge, is the goal of Christian spirituality.  With God's help we need to break through our illusions and see ourselves as we truly are in relation to God.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>33</id>
        <Source>Frederick Buechner </Source>
        <Contents>“The place that God calls us is that place where the world’s deep hunger and our own deep desire meet.”

Source:http://ignatianspirituality.com/making-good-decisions/vocations/the-voice-in-here/</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>34</id>
        <Source>Augustine</Source>
        <Contents>"Grant, Lord that I may know myself that I may know thee."</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>35</id>
        <Source>H. Norman Wright, Recovering from LOSSES in Life</Source>
        <Contents>Most people do not have a choice in their loss, but everyone has a choice in their recovery.  The change in your identity, relationships, new roles, and even abilities can be either positive or negative.  This is where you have a choice....Since life is full of losses, we have the choice of doing something constructive or destructive with our loss.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>36</id>
        <Source>Corrie Ten Boom, The Hiding Place</Source>
        <Contents>There is no pit so deep that God's love is not deeper still.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>37</id>
        <Source>David G. Benner, The Gift of Being Yourself</Source>
        <Contents>Our calling is therefore the way of being that is both best for us and best for the world.  This is what Frederick Buechner means when he states that "the place God calls you to is the place where your deep gladness and the world's deep hunger meet."</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/19/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>38</id>
        <Source>William Willimon</Source>
        <Contents>It's tough to be on the receiving end of love, God's or anyone else's.  It requires that we see our lives not as our possessions, but as gifts.  "Nothing is more repugnant to capable, reasonable people than grace," wrote John Wesley a long time ago.
- excerpt from "The God We Hardly Knew" by William Willimon, as included in the book, Watch For The Light: Readings for Advent and Christmas.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>39</id>
        <Source>-Francis Chan, Crazy Love</Source>
        <Contents>Isn't life always fragile?...If life were stable, I'd never need God's help.  Since it's not, I reach out for Him regularly.  I am thankful for the unknowns and that I don't have control, because it makes me run to God.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>40</id>
        <Source>-James B. Smith, THE GOOD AND BEAUTIFUL GOD</Source>
        <Contents>In our spiritual life we cannot do anything important in a hurry.
     When we are in a hurry--which comes from overextension--we find ourselves unable to live with awareness and kindness.  God never calls us, as Richard Foster likes to say,"into a life of panting feverishness."  </Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>41</id>
        <Source>Oswald Chambers, My Utmost For His Highest, Oct. 10 Reading</Source>
        <Contents>All God's revelations are sealed until they are opened to us by obedience.  You will never get them open by philosophy or thinking.  Immediately you obey, a flash of light comes.  Let God's truth work in you by soaking in it, not by worrying into it...Obey God in the thing He shows you, and instantly the next thing is opened up. </Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>42</id>
        <Source>Oswald Chambers, My Utmost For His Highest, Aug. 4 Reading</Source>
        <Contents>We must never allow anything to injure our relationship with God; if it does get injured we must take time and get it put right.  The main thing about Christianity is not the work we do, but the relationship we maintain and the atmosphere produced by that relationship.  That is all God asks us to look after, and it is the one thing that is being continually assailed.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>9/4/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>43</id>
        <Source>-James B. Smith, THE GOOD AND BEAUTIFUL GOD</Source>
        <Contents>Too many of us are trying to serve God without listening to God.  There will be time to serve, but listening to Jesus always takes precedence.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>44</id>
        <Source>Elisabeth Elliot, www.ElisabethElliot..org</Source>
        <Contents>God came down and lived in this same world as a man. He showed us how to live in this world, subject to its vicissitudes and necessities, that we might be changed-not into an angel or a storybook princess, not wafted into another world, but changed into saints in this world. The secret is Christ in me, not me in a different set of circumstances.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>6/13/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>45</id>
        <Source>Eugene Peterson, The Message</Source>
        <Contents>"I don't think the way you think.  The way you work isn't the way I work," declares God, "For as the sky soars high above the earth, so the way I work surpasses the way you work, and the way I think is beyond the way you think." - Isaiah 55:8-11</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>46</id>
        <Source>Quoted by Bruce Shelley, Church History in Plain Lang,, 3rd Ed.</Source>
        <Contents>"God of Abraham, God of Isaac, God of Jacob, not of the philosophers and scholars.  Certainty, certainty, feeling, joy, peace.  God of Jesus Christ..."

-Blaise Pascal, The year of grace 1654</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>47</id>
        <Source>Ann Voskamp, One Thousand Gifts, p. 203</Source>
        <Contents>It's impossible to give thanks and simultaneously feel fear.  This is the anti-anxiety medicine I try to lay in my wide-open palm every day.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>1/26/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>48</id>
        <Source>Psalm 42:1,2 NASB</Source>
        <Contents>As the deer pants for the water brooks, So my soul pants for You, O God. 

My soul thirsts for God, for the living God; When shall I come and appear before God?</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>2/2/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>49</id>
        <Source>Edward Hayes, Prayers for the Domestic Church</Source>
        <Contents>"We thank You, God of Mysterious Ways, that You have a holy design for each of us."
 -excerpt from "Blessed are You, Lord"</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/12/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>50</id>
        <Source>St. Irenaeus, excerpt  from "Potter and Clay"</Source>
        <Contents>It is  not you who shape God;
It is God who shapes you.

(Based on Jeremiah 18:1-10)</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>51</id>
        <Source>Oswald Chambers, My Utmost For His Highest, Oct. 10 Reading</Source>
        <Contents>All God's revelations are sealed until they are opened to us by obedience...Obey God in the thing He shows you, and instantly the next thing is opened up.  One reads tomes on the work of the Holy Spirit, when five minutes of drastic obedience would make things as clear as sunbeam.
</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>52</id>
        <Source>Anthony de Mello</Source>
        <Contents>Behold God beholding you...and smiling.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>53</id>
        <Source>Eugene Peterson, The Message Bible</Source>
        <Contents>Be generous.  Give to the poor.  Get yourselves a bank that can't go bankrupt, a bank in heaven far from bank robbers, safe from embezzlers, a bank you can bank on.  It's obvious, isn't it?  The place where your treasure is, is the place you will most want to be, and end up being.
-Luke 12:33-34</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>54</id>
        <Source>Oswald Chambers, My Utmost For His Highest, Sept. 10 Reading</Source>
        <Contents>The private relationship of worshiping God is the great essential of [character] fitness...Worship aright in your private relationships, then when God sets you free you will be ready, because in the unseen life which no one saw but God you have become perfectly fit, and when the strain comes you can be relied upon by God.
-excerpt from Sept. 10 reading</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>55</id>
        <Source>Ann Voskamp</Source>
        <Contents>What if we wanted to be beautiful more than we wanted to buy beautiful?

The enemy tempts that stuff is what makes us lovely — when the Truth is surrender makes us the loveliest and what is more lovely than love? Love, it knows no other way than to give away.
 excerpt from 11/15/11 post at www.aholyexperience.com</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>56</id>
        <Source>Brennan Manning, quoted in WATCH  FOR THE LIGHT: Readings for Advent &amp; Christmas</Source>
        <Contents>"Unless you...become like little children, you will never enter the kingdom of heaven" (Matt. 18:3).  Jesus is not suggesting that heaven is a vast playground for infants.  Children are our model because they have no claim of heaven.  If they are close to God, Simon Tugwell says, "it is not because they are innocent, but they are incompetent..."
 
Excerpt from "Shipwrecked at the Stable" by Brennan Manning</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>57</id>
        <Source>Abraham Lincoln</Source>
        <Contents>The best thing about the future is that it only comes one day at a time.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>6/15/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>58</id>
        <Source>St. Augustine</Source>
        <Contents>There can only be two basic loves: the love of God unto the forgetfulness of self, or the love of self unto the forgetfulness...of God.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>6/23/2012</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>59</id>
        <Source>John 11:25,26 NASB</Source>
        <Contents>Jesus said to her, "I am the resurrection and the life; he who believes in Me will live even if he dies, and everyone who lives and believes in Me will never die.  Do you believe this? </Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
    <Quote>
        <id>60</id>
        <Source>William Willimon</Source>
        <Contents>It's tough to be on the receiving end of love, God's or anyone else's.  It requires that we see our lives not as our possesssions, but as gifts.  "Nothing is more repugnant to capable, reasonable people than grace," wrote John Wesley a long time ago.
- excerpt from "The God We Hardly Knew" by William Willimon, as included in the book, Watch For The Light: Readings for Advent and Christmas.</Contents>
        <LastDisplayed>12/28/2011</LastDisplayed>
    </Quote>
</Quotes>